ABOUT ME

I am a well-rounded Python developer with over 5 years of experience in data science and web development teams. I believe in building things right, building the right things, and working in a sustainable way. That means caring about code quality and testing, releasing small and iterating, practicing open communication and always reflecting on my processes. Looking for a new position where I can make a difference.

WORK EXPERIENCE

SEPTEMBER 2018 - PRESENT

Senior Software Engineer (self-employed), London/remote

Delivering data science, data engineering, GIS and backend projects. Selected experience:

- Backend and systems engineer at the Link Institute for Market Research.
- Project leader at the Open Humans Foundation. Responsible for integrating Google Fit as a data source.
- GIS expert for Deutsche Welle. Consulted on article about the originating locations of fires in recent years.
- Data journalism project: Is London a forest?

March 2017 - August 2018

Senior Software Engineer at siroop, Zürich

Worked in the data science and the web development team of a Swiss e-commerce platform with thousands of sales every day.

Full Stack Web development

- Built critical features from scratch (voucher and promotion support, custom brand pages, integration of analytics tracking) using Django, Flask and RESTful services
- Extended existing functionality (product pages, CMS service and payment system) practicing TDD and pair programming
- Optimized test running time, local deployments with dockercompose and other aspects of the day to day development process
- Updated and deployed new AWS infrastructure (lambdas, Kinesis stream, DynamoDB) using Terraform
- Participated and led agile ceremonies (stand-ups, retrospectives)
- Acted as deputy team lead for a team of 7 and mentored more junior engineers

Data Engineering

- Launched personalized product recommendations to production
- Worked closely with data scientists to build a tool library
- Introduced and set up airflow as a pipeline manager for the recurring jobs
- Introduced and set up databricks as a development environment
- Did troubleshooting for scaling and cluster issues the data scientists faced (pySpark and pandas)



□ Ariadni-Karolina Alexiou
 ∴ 17 Bessemer Place, London SE
 ⊕ +44 73 83 001 288

(a) +44 73 83 001 288(b) carolinegr@gmail.com

http://www.github.com/carolinux

WORK EXPERIENCE CONTD.

November 2015 - February 2017

Lead Data Engineer at Tracktics GmbH, Zürich

Responsible for overseeing the extracting of insights from GPS and sensor data, collected from a tracker worn by football players in the field.

- Built the production data pipeline. It automatically processed the raw data (various stages, eg: MATLAB binary, Jupyter notebooks and python modules, chained together with celery)
- Launched various additional tools (heatmap generator, football pitch locator) to production
- Designed and oversaw the collection of test data to evaluate our algorithms
- Built evaluation into the data pipeline (in a way that externals could use it, and internals could easily create new report templates for new metrics)
- Built a library of common functionality together with the data scientists and mentored junior engineers

SEPTEMBER 2013 - JUNE 2015

Software Engineer at Teralytics AG, Zürich

Worked as a software engineer, extracting insights from mobile phone data and supporting my colleagues to do so.

- Created data pipelines to go from raw data to automatically updating web dashboards in production
- Created interactive visualizations of geospatial data (using PostGIS, d3, QGIS) for our customers
- Contributed to (and became co-maintainer) of an open source tool to visualize geotemporal data
- Built a library to unify access to diverse data sources

SELECTED CONFERENCES AND ARTICLES

- 2017 Speaker at PyData Berlin conference:
 Patterns for Collaboration between Data Scientists
 and Software Engineers
 video | article
- 2016 Published reflections on the future of Data Pipelines and the future of Python for Data Science
- 2015 Tutorial (Python): Exploring a UFO sightings dataset
- 2015 Article: Common mistakes with Python and Big Data
- 2015 Workshop on visualizing geotemporal data2014 Presented published paper at VLDB 2014
- 2014 Speaker at PyData Berlin conference on Mall Analytics (from prototype to product)

EDUCATION

2011 - 2013 **Master of Science**

COMPUTER SCIENCE ETH Zürich

GPA: 5.5/6 (also received scholarship)

2007 - 2011 Bachelor of Science

COMPUTER SCIENCE University of Athens

GPA: 9.3/10 - Top graduate in fall 2011

SELECTED FREELANCE OR OTHER WORK

Node Developer for SignedBlock, Athens

Extended and dockerized a program for live collection of data from the cryptocurrency market.

QGIS Plugin Developer for OpenGis.ch, Zürich

Responsible for developing Python plugins for geospatial data management.

Python and Data Engineering Tutor, online

Micro-consulting via codementor.io on several data science/engineering projects.

Mentor at Andela, online

Mentored junior programmers in Python, testing and programming patterns to prepare them for working remotely.

Data Consultant for New Incentives, Zürich

Created a data pipeline in Scala to sync data daily across mobile devices and Google spreadsheets.

Software Engineering Intern, Google Zürich

Migrated a feature of Youtube Analytics to the new backend.

LANGUAGES

English, German and Spanish in full professional capacity. Greek as mother tongue, some French.

Personal Interests

Painting (have some professional training), Social Science, Traveling. I have combined my thinking/practice as a programmer with those of being an artist to create a Drawing for Techies Workshop, which I have run multiple times in Switzerland, Germany and the UK.